

Ph.D candidate in the German Center for Integrative Biodiversity Research (iDiv) Halle – Jena – Leipzig. I am working on tree diversity effects on soil microbial community and soil functioning including litter decomposition and soil carbon storage.

<u>Research interest:</u> BEF, ecosystem ecology, soil ecology, microbial ecology, food web ecology, synthesis

Rémy Beugnon

Address: Hans-Oster-Str. 17,

04157 Leipzig (Germany)

Phone: +49 1520 33 43 829 E-Mail: remy.beugnon@idiv.de Twitter: @BeugnonRemy

Web: https://remybeugnon.netlify.app/

Languages

French – native English – fluent

Field skills

- Subtropical China field campaign
- Litterfall, insect and soil sampling
- Performing decomposition experiment

Lab skills

- Microbial biomass (e.g., PLFA)
- Microbial physiology (e.g., MicroResp®)
- Insect identification

Analysis skills

- Multivariate analysis (e.g. PCA, RDA)
- Frequentist statistic (e.g. linear, nonlinear, mixed effects models)
- Spatio-temporal analysis
- Structural Equation Modelling
- Network analysis (basic knowledge)
- Bayesian statistics (basic knowledge)

Programming skills

R – advanced
Bash – basic knowledge
LaTeX – basic knowledge
Python/HTML/SQL/GIS – basic knowledge

Research experiences

07.2018 to now

Ph.D thesis - German Center for Integrative Biodiversity Research (iDiv) Halle – Jena – Leipzig , Leipzig (Germany)

Tree diversity effects on soil microbial communities and soil carbon dynamics

<u>Supervision:</u> Dr. Simone Cesarz, Prof. Dr. Nico Eisenhauer <u>Main topics</u>: tree interactions effects on litterfall, decomposition, microbial community composition and functions and soil carbon storage

01.2018 to 06.2018

MSc. thesis - Institut des Sciences de l'Evolution de Montpellier ISME, Montpellier (France)

Modelling non-trophic interactions effects on community dynamics.

Supervision: Dr. Sonia Kéfi, Dr. Vasilis Dakos

04.2017 to 07.2017

Internship - Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences (SLU), Umeå (Sweden)

Root trait effects of alpine plant communities on plant-soil feedback effects performed in two greenhouse experiments.

Supervision: Dr. Paul Kardol

Education

09.2017-06.2018

Master's degree in biology, ecology and evolution – Université de Montpellier, France

09.2014-11.2018

Agricultural engineering diploma – Montpellier SupAgro, France

Publications

2019

Beugnon, Rémy; Steinauer, Katja; Barnes, Andrew D.; Ebeling, Anne; Roscher, Christiane; Eisenhauer, Nico (2019): *Plant functional trait identity and diversity effects on soil meso-and macrofauna in an experimental grassland*. In Advances in ecological research 61, p. 163-184. DOI: 10.1016/bs.aecr.2019.06.004

Cesarz, Simone; Schulz, Annika Eva; **Beugnon, Rémy**; Eisenhauer, Nico (2019): *Testing soil nematode extraction efficiency using different variations of the Baermann-funnel method*. In Soil Organisms 91 (2), p. 61. DOI: 10.25674%2Fso91201

2021

Beugnon, Rémy† & Du Jianqing†; Cesarz, Simone; Jurburg, Stephanie D.; Pang, Zhe; Singavarapu, Bala; Wubet, Tesfaye; Xue, Kai; Wangs, Yanfen^S & Eisenhauers, Nico^S (2021): *Tree diversity and soil chemical properties drive the linkages between soil microbial community and ecosystem functioning*. In ISME Communications 1 (1), 1-11. DOI: 10.1038/s43705-021-00040-0

Beugnon, Rémy, Emma Ladouceur, Marie Sünnemann, Simone Cesarz^S & Nico Eisenhauer^S (2021): *Diverse forests are cool: promoting diverse forest to mitigate carbon emission and climate change*. In Journal of Sustainable Agriculture and Environment

Phillips, Helen R. P.; Bach, Elizabeth M.; Bartz, Marie L. C.; Bennett, Joanne M.; **Beugnon, Rémy**; Briones, Maria J. I. et al. (2021): *Global data on earthworm abundance, biomass, diversity and corresponding environmental properties.* In Scientific Data 8 (1), p. 136. DOI: 10.1038/s41597-021-00912-z.

Singavarapu, Bala; **Beugnon, Rémy**; Bruelheide, Helge; Cesarz, Simone; Du, Jianqing; Eisenhauer, Nico; Guo, Liang-Dong; Nawaz, Ali; Wang, Yanfen; Xue, Kai; Wubet, Tesfaye (2021): *Tree mycorrhizal type and tree diversity shape the forest soil microbiome*. In Environmental Microbiology

Thouvenot, Lise; Ferlian, Olga; **Beugnon, Rémy;** Künne, Tom; Lochner, Alfred; Thakur, Madhav P.; Türke, Manfred; Eisenhauer, Nico (2021): *Do invasive earthworms affect the functional traits of native plants?* In Frontiers in plant science 12, p. 424. DOI: 10.3389/fpls.2021.627573

In preparation

Beugnon, Rémy; Bu, Wensheng; Bruelheide, Helge; Davrinche, Andréa; Du, Jianqing; Haider, Sylvia; Kunz, Matthias; von Oheimb, Goddert; Perles-Garcia, Maria D.; Saadani, Mariem; Scholten, Thomas; Seitz, Steffen; Singavarapu, Bala; Trogisch, Stefan; Wang, Yanfen; Wubet, Tesfaye; Xue, Kai; Yang, Bo; Cesarz, SimoneS & Eisenhauer, NicoS (**under review**): Abiotic and biotic drivers of scale-dependent tree trait effects on soil microbial biomass and soil carbon concentration. In Ecological Monographs

Beugnon, Rémy; Eisenhauer, Nico; Bruelheide, Helge; Davrinche, Andréa; Du, Jianqing; Haider, Sylvia; Haehn, Georg; Saadani, Mariem; Singavarapu, Bala; Sünnemann, Marie; Thouvenot, Lise; Wang, Yanfen; Wubet, Tesfaye; Xue, Kai; Cesarz, Simone (in prep.): *Tree diversity effects on litter decomposition are mediated by litterfall and microbial processes.*

Schnabel, Florian†; **Beugnon, Rémy**†; Bo, Yang†; Castro Izaguirre, Nadia Cristina; Cesarz, Simone; Eisenhauer, Nico; Garcia, Maria Dolores Perles; Haehn, Georg; Härdtle, Werner; Huang, Yuanyuan; Kunz, Matthias; Liu, Xiaojuan; Niklaus, Pascal A.; von Oheimb, Goddert; Pietsch, Katherina A.; Richter, Ronny; Schmid, Bernhard; Trogisch, Stefan; Wirth, Christian; Ma, Keping^S & Bruelheide Helge^S (in prep.): *The role of tree species richness for temperature buffering below forest canopies*.

Reviewer

Nature Communications, Scientific Reports, Pedobiologia, Soil Organisms

Teaching

2021 - Introduction to stats in R for bachelors and master students (12h)

Outreach

2019 to 2021 - Guest editor for Frontiers for Young Minds collection "Soil biodiversity" **2021** - Contribution to the Leipzig's Long Night of Sciences

Oral presentations and invited talks

2018 - "Effect of non-trophic interactions on community dynamics", Model in Ecology and Evolution conference – Monpellier, France

2019 - "Effects of tree functional diversity on soil community and function", iDiv conference – Leipzig, Germany

2020

"To a mechanistical understanding of plant diversity effects on soil fauna community", Laboratoire d'écologie alpine (LECA) – Grenoble, France

"Abiotic and biotic mediations of scale dependent tree traits effects on soil carbon concentrations", BES annual meeting 2020 – Virtual

Professionalization courses

2021 - Third Party Funding Opportunities

2020

- Scientific writing
- Introduction to ggplot2
- Good scientific practices

2019

- Structural Equation Modeling
- Nematode identification course

Participation to institutional activities

09.2021 - Ph.D representative for iDiv Equal Opportunity comity

2021 - Interviews of senior researcher about "transdisciplinary research" for the GfÖ Twitter account **2018-2021**

- Organization of afterwork activities for the Experimental Interaction Ecology (EIE) working group
- Organization of welcome packages for new members of the EIE working group